FARNOOD FOROUDI

Product Designer, UI/UX Designer



+98 (912) 205-4840 +98 (936) 476-5685

Skype ID: farnud.ir

foroudi@gmail.com

http://farnood.design

PROFILE

As a Product Designer, I've been working with several great Iranian companies like Mapna Group, Digikala, Parsian Bank, Peyke Bartar, Mellat Bank, ADP and a number of tech startups in past 7 years. I've designed more than 10 products such as mobile apps, websites and services which have been used by millions of Iranians around the world.

EXPERIENCE

Product Design Manager, Kian Capital Management – 2018-Present

I manage the process of product design and my focus is on delivering the Kian Digital Bank application, which is a revolutionary mobile banking app with unique features introduced for the first time in the country.

Product Design Manager, Dunro – 2017-2018

As a Product Design Manager, I lead a team of 3 designers. We are responsible for what the future of the product will be, and how it will look like, through user research, analyzing usage feedback, sketching ideas, prototyping, A/B testing and delivering assets to Dev team by highly detailed visual designs.

I've designed the Dunro's new social network and its gamification platform, rewarding system and Dunro Market.

Dunro helps people find the best and nearest local businesses. It is the most popular location-based social network of Iran.

Product Designer, Dunro – 2015-2017

I was responsible for improving Dunro's (formerly iBartar) usability and product design, I managed to fully redesign the mobile apps, by improving the user experience, creating its design language, participating at product strategies and shaping the product's road-map in the way it is now. I was responsible for the re-branding project of iBartar to Dunro. I also founded the company's content team.

UI/UX Designer, Digikala.com – 2015

As a Visual Designer, my mission was to design the Digikala iOS application from concept to implementation. I designed the product based on user researches and tests in Digikala's UX lab. Successfully launched the iOS application which won the Iranian UX Awards on 2015. Digikala.com is the biggest online store in Iran and MENA region.

Co-Founder and Head of Design, Seeb Mobile Technologies – 2013-2015

Co-founded a digital agency called Seeb due to huge amount of mobile app projects in Iran's tech market back on 2013. Collaboratively designed more than 10 mobile apps and websites for some biggest Iranian companies and some hot startups like:

- · Parsian Bank (Mobile App)
- · Fidilio (Popular Restaurant Finder)
- Narengi (Apartment Rental Platform like AirBnB in Iran app and Website soon to be launched)
- Buyex (Iranian Fashion and Apparel Online Store mobile app)
- MBRI Events (Official App of Monetary and Banking Research Institute)

Self-Owned Projects

- Tehran Air (delightful award winning health mobile app for monitoring Tehran's air quality)
- SeebStore (popular catalog of Appstore apps in Farsi language which was helping Iranian users to buy from the Appstore. is currently shut down)
- Golabi (a popular simple trivia game for iOS)
- · Eventak (an event management application)

FARNOOD FOROUDI

Product Designer, UI/UX Designer

Web Designer, Nasb Niroo Co. (Mapna group) - 2012-2014

Designed and developed the company's website. Successfully Redesigned the company's internal portal which was based on Microsoft SharePoint. Collaboratively designed and implemented the company's business workflows and forms on SharePoint workflows, also successfully implement projects about information architecture, workflow forms usability and user experience tests like card sorting. Also had teaching experience on Microsoft SharePoint to employees. Mapna Group is the biggest Iranian international holding in the fields of Energy, Oil and Petrochemicals.

EDUCATION

B.S in Software Computer Engineering, Shomal University of Amol, Mazandaran, Iran - 2005-2011

Diploma in Math and Physics, Sama 4 High School, Tehran, Iran

CERTIFICATES

Microsoft MCTS: SharePoint 2010, Configuration

TUV NORD: Internal Audit of Integrated Management Systems (IMS)

PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

Mentor of Tehran's First Educational Startup Weekend

Two Times Winner of Iran Web and Mobile Festival